# MARIA MCGLADE SEGOVIA

# **MARKETING MANAGER**

+34 618 821 295 · mariamcglade@gmail.com · linkedin.com/in/maria-mcglade

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Data-savvy marketing professional with a proven track record in product launches and data analysis. Fluent in four languages, combines data analytics, UX insights and go-to-market expertise. Turning ideas into campaigns that engage, inspire, and deliver results.

### **KEY SKILLS**

- · Campaign management
- Data analysis and reporting
- Marketing automation

- · Project management
- · Content marketing and SEO
- UX and customer research

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Product Marketing Communications Specialist**

Elekta (Healthtech)

Nov 2023 - Present

London, UK

- Led the global launch of new software campaigns, increasing qualified leads by 30%
- Monitored competitor and market activity and refined messaging accordingly, leading to a 15% uplift in campaign engagement
- Developed targeted content and materials that boosted customer engagement metrics by 20%

### **Marketing Database & Reporting Intern**

Elekta (Healthtech)

May 2023 - Nov 2023

London, UK

- Built dashboards in Salesforce and QlikSense to monitor campaign metrics, enabling teams to make datadriven decisions and cutting reporting time by 30%
- Cleaned and updated Salesforce data, improving targeting accuracy and reducing duplicate records by 25%
- Built automated email campaigns in Salesforce that increased open rates by 10% for target audiences

**Librarian** | While studying H-FARM (Education)

Sep 2022 - May 2023

Venice, Italy

Bartender & Social Media Manager | While studying

Montpeliers Ltd (Hospitality) Edinburgh, UK

Jun 2019 - Dec 2020 Edinburgh, UK

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Master of Science, Digital Marketing & Data Analytics

H-FARM College (University of Chichester)

Sep 2022 - Nov 2023

Venice, Italy

- Participated in challenges and hackathons with De'Longhi & Juventus
- · Nurtured curiosity for UX & data

# **Bachelor of Arts, Business Administration with Marketing**

Edinburgh Napier University

Sep 2017 - Oct 2022 Edinburgh, UK

## ADDITIONAL SKILLS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

Languages: English (native), Spanish (native), Italian (C2) and French (B2)

**Certifications**: Analyse Data with Python, CAD and Digital Manufacturing, Start Up Lab, Project Management for Innovation, Economics of Blockchain